LUCAS GANSBERG

Father, husband, tinkerer, fullstack software engineer



(541)-591-8020



☐ lucas.gansberg@outlook.com

Add Link here after export



in www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-gansberg

SKILLS

- React
- NodeJS
- Terraform
- Docker
- CI/CD
- Figma/Sketch
- Javascript/TypeScript
- Golang
- C# .NET
- C++
- HTML/CSS
- GraphQL
- AWS
- REST

EDUCATION

B.S. Software Engineering Oregon Institute of Technology

SUMMARY

Results-driven Software Engineer with 12 years of industry experience. For the past three years I've managed a team of four highly skilled engineers, working on a variety of projects. I'm currently interested in leading another skilled group of engineers or working by their side.

OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a dynamic engineering role where I can drive positive change and contribute to high-quality software development. Whether leading a team or tackling challenging projects, I am committed to delivering innovative solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Manager

March 2021 - March 2024

- Led a team of 4 developers responsible for 5 critical internal platforms, SDKs, libraries, and customer support.
- Fostered a collaborative environment, ensuring seamless communication across cross-functional teams.
- Spearheaded the re-architecture of our internal Identity Provider (IdP) provisioning platform.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to define requirements, streamline processes, and enhance security.
- Developed and executed engineering roadmaps, aligning technical initiatives with product goals.
- · Managed tasks, prioritized features, and ensured timely delivery of enhancements.



Senior Software Engineer III

May 2019 - March 2021

- Built an internal AWS-style console, providing a centralized hub for technical products and documentation.
 - Simplified access to critical tools, improving efficiency for the entire organization.
- f.
- Stood up an internal data enrichment metric service, enhancing data quality and decision-making.
 - Leveraged active directory and analytics to drive insights.
- Collaborated with UX designers to create intuitive interfaces.



(intel) Senior Software Engineer II

March 2016 - May 2019

- Designed a user-friendly UI to manage server rack resources dynamically.
- Optimized resource allocation based on workload requirements (compute, storage, memory).
- · Proficiently used Golang, gRPC, and React/Redux to implement cuttingedge solutions.



Software Engineer

July 2011 - March 2016

Software engineer focused on test automation, validating wireless standards/protocols, wireless certification, under the automation tools team. Used C# .NET, C++, and a variety of other software languages.